

marc@aworkofmarc.com | 323-658-8472 | Los Angeles, CA 90048

SUMMARY

24 years extensive art direction/design experience as it relates to website design, print, monthly emailers, one-offs and piece graphics, ad badges, social media graphics, corporate branding design, photography (product, lifestyle, portrait) and videography. Expert experience with complete Adobe CC Master Collection, Lightroom, DXO, OnOne, Premiere and After Effects software, PowerPoint, Key One, Google Slides (+ suite) Word Press / admin, etc. Self-starter, assertive, flexible, enthusiastic, proactive, organized, responsible, timely, highly motivated with a 'can do' attitude. Enjoy collaborating and mentoring diverse teams. Experience managing teams 2 to 12 people.

PORTFOLIO http://www.aworkofmarc.com | LINKEDIN http://www.linkedin.com/in/aworkofmarc

SKILLS

- Art Direction / Graphic Design
- Producer / Studio Management
- Website / Print Design
- Photography / Post Prod.

- Video / Post Prod.
- Adobe Photoshop / CC Creative Suite
- Digital Illustration
- Website Admin / Webmaster

EXPERIENCE -

AWORKOFMARC

Los Angeles, CA ART DIRECTOR / DESIGNER / PRODUCER 10/2008 - Current Design Agency Studio/Consulting. Responsible for the art direction, design and complete operation of the freelance design studio in every phase of the project and throughout the life cycle of the deliverables. Worked facilitating initial client consultation, conceptual and design, photography etc. Annotating wireframes, mapping content requirements and website's real estate sections, information architecture, some minor front end development to production design; all the efficient management of design projects in the areas of web sites and print. Conceptualize and design logos and corporate branding, marketing materials, sales decks, presentation books, proposals, catalogs, always ensuring corporate branding and visual design consistency. Created time forecasts and budgets projections, liaison with outside contractors and vendors, built schedules, managed development teams. Clients: DISNEY, UNIVERSAL STUDIOS, SONY PICTURES TELEVISION, Display Krafters, Concord Displays, ASB.tv AddVal Inc., etc.

UMB ADVANSTAR

Santa Monica, CA ART DIRECTOR /DESIGNER 03/2008 - 09/2008

PATH CONNECT LLC

Los Angeles, CA ART DIRECTOR 03/2008 - 12/2008 Art directed and designed websites and print material for multiple tradeshow facets, including Comikaze Expo, National Pharma companies, International Fashion, Motorcycle, and Auto Shows, Dealer Expo, and more. Working with both in house and with overseas development teams to ensure cohesive branding look and feel.

Path Connect was a social networking startup company along the lines of MySpace.com. Responsible for Art Direction (hands-on) redesign of their flagship social networking website as well as Art Direction and design for additional projects for their parent company Visalus.com – everything from developing the functionality and information architecture and then built the wireframes from the approved information architecture specifications for online presence & internal UX design.

- Developed additional (and furthered the original) company branding guidelines.
- · Worked with marketing dept.
- To develop online ads.
- General maintenance: ftp, edited CSS, html functionality.
- · Created logos and general advertising button / badges.
- Directed rich media banner development.
- Compiled branding style guides (internet and print).
- Lead a team of 2 to 6 designers in the production of graphic and animation assets all the while working closely with the backend development team.
- Conducted focus groups, facilitated Q & A teams, usability testing.

Part of the globally focused marketing team and responsible for a wide variety of projects from web site redesign and maintenance to company branding and print items including the design of flyers, business cards, stationery and magazine ads, developed and illustrated logos and technical diagrams, magazine ads, product box design.

- Designed tradeshow display booth and respective skins.
- Created computer soft phone (virtual).
- Built device diagrams and instruction pamphlets.
- Conducted focus groups regarding backend information architecture / UX design (admin and billing) and built wireframes from that information.
- Created and implemented UX design based on the above wireframes.
- Art Directed / designed SipTalk and Global Touch Telecom websites, including intranet
- Hand illustrated proprietary icons for industry standard devices.
- Created brochures, and quarterly newsletters, one sheets, flyers, marketing postcards, business cards etc.
- Managed teams from 2 to 5 people depending on the project.

Art Directed and designed for Universal Studios multiple business units including: SPENCER GIFTS, VERVE MUSIC GROUP, UNIVERSAL CLASSICS, CAPTAIN MORGAN RUM, AND BACK LOT STUDIO OPERATIONS, etc.

Duties included: project conception, direction, extensive hands—on design, while coordinating creative resources / process; streamlining current processes; developing and expediting new processes.

- Advocated design to Universal Studios business units (clients), worked with both internal and external software development teams and focus groups to analyze online user experience and content.
- Worked with Producers and Universal Studios business units integrating their requirements with current technology into design strategies; balancing UI (design) aesthetics with marketing dept.
- Requirements to ensure design integrity and cohesiveness.
- Established project goals, designed employee incentive plans.
- Interfaced with business associates promoting design concepts, storyboarding, flow charts / information architecture and user experience.
- Managed Teams from 2 to 12 people depending on the project.

For multiple business clients including NISSAN-USA, PATAGONIA, QUIKSILVER etc. Several smaller companies.

- Duties included Art Direction and project conception, building / implementing annotated wireframes, coordination of the creative process with Producers and Development Teams, design advocacy, creative resource and personnel coordination, and hands-on design.
- Integrated technology and client's business requirements into design strategies,

GLOBALTOUCH TELECOM

Los Angeles, CA SENIOR DESIGNER / PRODUCER 01/2004 - 11/2007

UNIVERSAL STUDIOS

Universal City, CA
INTERNET ART DIRECTOR / DESIGNER,
ART DIRECTOR
05/2000 - 12/2002

MAGNET INTERACTIVE

Culver City, CA
SENIOR DESIGNER / PRODUCER,
ART DIRECTOR
11/1999 - 03/2000

balancing UI, marketing, aesthetics and creative resource and personnel coordination.

- Established project goals with Producers over saw multiple projects (interfacing mainly Nissan but also Quiksilver and Patagonia) to ensure design integrity and quality standards.
- Managed, lead and motivated the creative team from 1 to 6 people depending on the project.

Art Direction and design. Created 'hands-on' web page/site design and ongoing marketing graphics for several Disney business units (DISNEY EDUCATIONAL, DISNEY RECORDS, BACKSTREET RECORDS, LYRIC STREET RECORDS, DISNEYLAND, DISNEYWORLD) character development, illustration and Flash animation.

- Provided Art Direction for both in-house and acted as liaison for sub-contracted web site development.
- Responsible for design side delivery of the completed, comprehensive, high-quality
 web site solutions that provided the various Disney units with strategies that
 supported (or created) the brand identity and met their mission critical objectives.
- Involved at every stage of the web projects from conducting initial focus groups to analyzing online user experience and content.
- Wireframing and information architecture development.
- Represented Disney Online in on-going consultation with both Disney's individual business units and outside developers.
- Built teams per project including working with Producers and software development teams, all the way to final Q & A testing.
- Worked with Producers and business units integrating their requirements with current technology into UI design while providing and keeping aesthetics / branding up to Disney's par.
- Worked with marketing dept. to ensure message integrity.
- Interfaced with Disney's B2B clients and related business associates detailing design concepts, story-boarding.
- Established project goals, budgets, employee incentive plans.
- Managed Teams from 1 to 10 people depending on the project.

EDUCATION

DISNEY ONLINE

N. Hollywood, CA

ART DIRECTOR

06/1997 - 11/1999

SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY | SYRACUSE, NY Bachelor of Arts

